[Music]
So I'm a clinical cardiologist and I run
a dedicated cardiology clinic for
pediatric age and adults with various
inherited neuromuscular disorders.
Most of the patients are Duchenne or Becker
but there's a mixture of other conditions
and I work very closely with
John Wharton muscle team at the
International Center for Life in Newcastle.
The main focus of my research
for the last... well, nearly ten years
has been a randomized study seeing whether
protective treatment for the heart
in Duchenne patients can delay the onset
of heart muscle weakness or change
the trajectory of left ventricular dysfunction
So, eighty five boys were recruited
between the ages of five and thirteen
and followed for a minimum of three years.
We treated them with a combination of
perindopril — that's an ACE inhibitor
and a beta blocker : prepared bisoprolol.
and there was a placebo comparator group.
Somewhat disappointingly, the results do not show
any group benefit after three years of treatment
but we think that's partly explained
by the fact that younger patients,
and the variation in the age of onset of muscle weakness
won't show in a three-year time period
So we're hoping to follow the patients for longer.
There are beginning to be some changes
which may prove to be interesting but
at the moment we have to conclude,
that after three years of treatment,
there is no difference between active and placebo treatment.
So essentially, if I'm a scientist I would say that the study is negative.
If on the other hand I'm a clinician I believe that
the treatments are beneficial for the heart in Duchenne
because we know already that once we detect
muscle weakness at an early stage,
the trajectory of the decline in heart function is helped and slowed
by the treatments we were testing.
So I think it's more an effect of saying
the earlier you start a treatment,
the harder it is to show a benefit!
The AFM of course is pivotal in providing
funding for a wide range of research,
and it also ensures a balance between
the investigation of different conditions.
The AFM I think is essential to maintaining
the momentum that's been built up over recent years,
and is allowing translation of research,
and the relevance of basic science and molecular biology
into the clinic much faster...
So, the research funding is critical,
the networking is critical,
the meetings under the auspices of the organization
ensure spreading of information
much, much more rapidly than traditional methods!
[Music]